Register of the Sir Robert Hamilton Bruce Lockhart papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sir Robert Hamilton Bruce Lockhart papers
1895-2003
85039
Hoover Institution Archives
11 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize box, 1 oversize folder (5.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, diaries, notes, memoranda, photographs, and memorabilia relating to miscellaneous aspects of Anglo-Soviet relations during the Russian Revolution, British espionage in the Soviet Union during the Russian Revolution, miscellaneous aspects of British government activities during World War II (including Anglo-Czechoslovak relations), and personal affairs. Includes many letters by Baroness Moura Budberg, some letters by British espionage agent Sidney Reilly, and some material about him collected by Lockhart's son, Robin Bruce Lockhart.
Lockhart, Robert Hamilton Bruce, Sir, 1887-1970
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of some digital files in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or other digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1887 September 2 Born, Anstruther, Scotland
1912-1915 Vice-Consul, British Foreign Service, Moscow
1915-1917 Acting Consul-General, British Foreign service, Moscow
1918 January Head of Special Mission to the Soviet Government
1918 Sept.-Oct. Arrested by the Bolsheviks; released and exchanged for Maxim Litvinov
1919-1922 Commercial Secretary to British Legation, Prague, Czechoslovakia
1922-1928 Worked in banking in Central Europe
1929-1937 Member, Editorial Staff, Evening Standard (London)
1932 Author, Memoirs of a British Agent
1934 Author, Retreat from Glory
1936 Author, Return to Malaya
1937 Author, My Scottish Youth
1938 Author, Guns or Butter?
1939-1940 Director-General, Political Intelligence Department, British Foreign Office
1940-1941 British Representative with Provisional Czechoslovak government in London
1941-1945 Deputy Under-Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, British Foreign Office and Director-General of Political Warfare Executive
1943 Knighted, Order of St. Michael and St. George
1947 Author, Comes the Reckoning
1948 Author, My Rod My Comfort
1950 Author, The Marines Were There
1951 Author, Ján Masaryk Author, Scotch
1952 Author, My Europe
1955 Author, Your England
1957 Author, The Two Revolutions Friends, Foes and Foreigners
1960 Author, Giants Cast Long Shadows
1970 February 27 Died, Hove, England
Scope and Content Note
The Robert Bruce Hamilton Lockhart papers consist of correspondence, diaries, memoranda, notes, speeches and writings, photographs, and memorabilia relating to miscellaneous aspects of Anglo-Soviet relations during the Russian Revolution, British espionage in the Soviet Union during the Russian Revolution, miscellaneous aspects of British government activities during World War II (including Anglo-Czechoslovak relations), and personal affairs. Also included is some material about Lockhart collected by his son, Robin Bruce Lockhart.
The Biographical file includes material on Lockhart's role in the counter-revolutionary "Lockhart Plot" against the Soviet Union. This scheme to overthrow the Bolshevik government, with help from Sidney Reilly, resulted in Lockhart's arrest and subsequent sentencing to death on charges of espionage and sabotage. The Subject file contains information relating to the Chester Concession, which was a grant awarded by the Turkish National Assembly in 1923 April to the Ottoman-American Development Company giving it the right to develop Turkish natural resources, and a report on the role of the Polish government in Boris Savinkov's conspiracy against the Soviet Union.
The Sidney Reilly file contains material collected by Lockhart about this British espionage agent. It includes letters to and from Reilly, as well as a 1968 article about the search for Reilly. A related item in the Correspondence is a 1932 letter from Baroness Moura Budberg indicating that Reilly might still be alive.
The Great Britain Foreign Office documents series consists of dispatches relating to the situation in Czechoslovakia in 1946-1948. The bulk is from the British Embassy in Prague to the Foreign Office in London, but some from British Embassies elsewhere in Europe and the Soviet Union are included. Security-classified documents have been removed from this series, as required by law, until they can be declassified by government officials.
The Incremental materials series is arranged following the arrangement of the rest of the collection. These materials include the papers of Robin N. Bruce Lockhart, son of Robert H. Bruce Lockhart, who wrote a book about Sidney Reilly titled Ace of Spies.
Budberg, Moura.; Great Britain. Foreign Office.; Lockhart, Robin Bruce.; Reilly, Sidney George, 1874-1925.; Czechoslovakia.; Espionage, British--Soviet Union.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Great Britain.; Russia (Federation); Secret service--Great Britain.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.; World War, 1939-1945--Czechoslovakia.; World War, 1939-1945--Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Biographical file, 1911-1963
  Scope and Contents note
  Article, brochure, certificates, letter, memoranda, passes, passports, report, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Article by Victor Kravchenko, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Article on Robert Lockhart's role in counter-revolutionary plot against the Soviet Union, based on the author's interview with Ján Buinis. Contains a photographic reproduction of a note by Robert Lockhart requesting all personnel concerned to offer any assistance possible to Ján Buinis during his mission to "British Headquarters in Russia," 1912
  - Brochure to promote a movie based on British Agent by Robert Lockhart, 1934 September (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Certificate of confirmation issued by the British Church of St. Andrew, Moscow, 1912 May (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Certificate awarding the K.C.M.G. (Knight Commander of the Order of St. Michael and St. George), 1943 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Includes three letters relating to this membership, including a preliminary invitation from the Prime Minister's office, 1942-1962. Signed by George VI, the Earl of Athlone, and the Earl of Clarendon.
  - Civil service examination, 1911 July (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Printed copy
  - Letter from the Austrian Minister in London transmitting appointment as Honorary Consul General in London for Austria, 1927 May (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Memorandum from Robert Lockhart to Arthur Balfour on the internal situation in the Soviet Union. See Declassified British government records (box 12, folder 7)., 1918 November (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Memorandum from the U.S. Army recommending Sir Robert Bruce Lockhart for the Medal of Merit, 1945 September 21 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Passes, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Passports, 1918-1963 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Report on the "Lockhart Plot," with depositions of the accused, 1918 November 30 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    Holograph
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
    Includes signatures of Robin N. Bruce Lockhart, son of Robert Lockhart, and others.
- Correspondence, 1895-1971
  Letters and telegrams both received or written by Lockhart, and including some letters neither to nor from him, arranged alphabetically by correspondent
  - General
    - Childhood letters, 1895 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Telegrams to Robert Lockhart, 1934 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 1: 15)
      Includes Easter greetings to Robert Lockhart, n.d.; 3 postcards neither from nor to Robert Lockhart, ca. 1916; and a postcard to Robert Lockhart received at Evening Standard, 1935
  - Bark, Peter, Sir, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Beneš, Edvard, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    Photocopies and Christmas greetings
  - Bracken, Brendan, 1948 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Buchanan, George, Sir, 1926 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Budberg, Moura, Baroness
    - Undated (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - circa 1915-1918 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - circa 1919-1959 (Box-folder 1: 22)
    - After 1924 (probably) (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Caccia, Harold, Sir, 1964 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Carol, King of Romania, to President Edvard Beneš, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Eden, Anthony, 1939-1945 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Einzig, Paul, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Kerensky, Aleksandr, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Lascelles, Alan, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Lockhart, Rob, Lt.-Gen., Sir, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Lockhart, Robin Bruce, 1923-1969
    - Undated (Box-folder 1: 31)
      General note
      See also box 9 folder 2
    - 1923-1952 (Box-folder 1: 32)
    - 1953-1958 (Box-folder 1: 33-35)
    - 1959-1969 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
  - Louis Ferdinand, Prince of Prussia, 1933 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Marie, Queen of Romania, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    Letter written by Countess Irene Procofsin, Lady-in-Waiting
  - Masaryk, Ján, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    Printed quotation from Lao-tse with holograph note
  - Norton, Jean, undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Peake, Charles, Sir, 1947 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Peterson, Maurice, Sir, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Salisbury, Lord, 1955 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Spears, E. L., 1967 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    See also box 6 folder 25
  - West, Rebecca, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- Diaries, 1910-1962
  Miscellaneous diaries and photocopies of printed transcripts of diaries, arranged chronologically. The majority of Lockhart's diaries are located in the Beaverbrook Library and have been published in several volumes ( The Diaries of Sir Robert Bruce Lockhart, Kenneth Young, ed., London: Macmillan London Limited, 1973)
  - Originals
    - 1910 July - August (Box-folder 2: 12)
      Relates to travel from the Far East through Canada to England. Includes draft verse.
    - 1946 July 1 - 1954 June 28 (Box-folder 2: 13)
      Erratic entries from 1946 (primarily), 1947, 1948, 1950, and 1954
    - 1960 April 23 and May 12-13 (Box-folder 2: 14)
      Loose-leaf pages describing a visit with Sir Orme Sargent
  - Photocopies of printed transcripts of diaries, 1915-1962
    - 1915-1942 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - 1943-1962 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - 1943-1962 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Speeches and writings, 1907-1960
  Arranged chronologically. Many early works from and about the Soviet Union were written under the pseudonym of Jean d'Auvergne
  - General
    - Notebooks
      Contains entries on significant individuals and events, as well as quotations and other miscellany.
      - Undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - 1932 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - 1934 (Box-folder 3: 6)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 4: 1)
      - circa 1938 (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - 1938-1945 (Box-folder 4: 3)
      - 1940s (Box-folder 4: 4)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 4: 6)
        Includes some notes from 1943
      - 1950 (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Verse, loose-leaf holographs and notebooks, 1907-1913 (Box-folder 5: 4-6)
  - "Ordeal by Oratory", undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
    Mimeographed typescript co-authored with Alexander Kerensky
  - "The Slave of the White Poppy", undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
    Draft typescript
  - "Student-Life in Russia," Chambers's Journal, 1912 June (Box-folder 5: 9)
    Mimeographed copy of printed article
  - "The Russian Decadents," The Blue Book, 1912 September (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Miscellaneous columns, 1913-1915 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "The Continental Variety-Stage," parts I and II, The Englishwoman, 1913 January - February (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - "Ears of Rye," Chambers's Journal, 1913 March 1 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - "Ten Years of Russian Literature," The Englishwoman, 1913 August (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - "The Revolutionary: A Tale of the Russian Ballet," The Bystander, 1913 September 17 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    Mimeographed copy
  - Columns for The Bystander, 1913 March - 1914 May 20 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    Relate to Russian life and literature. Mimeographed and printed copies
  - "The Moscow Art Theatre", circa 1914 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - "Daddy", 1914 August 1 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    Typescript of a short story
  - "The Way of the English," The Royal Magazine, 1916 May (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - "Bolshevik Aims and Bolshevik Ideals", 1918-1919 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - "An Englishman Looks at the World," speech, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    Typescript
  - "James Simpson," article, circa 1930 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "End of an Epoch", 1938-1939 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    Autobiographical typescript
  - "Inside Wartime Russia," radio broadcast, 1942 May 19 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - "The Wandering Scot," speech, circa 1950 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - "Founder's Day, Fettes College," speech, 1953 June 27 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - "Britain's Place in the World Today," speech, 1953 September (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - "Queen and Commonwealth," speech, the Societe Franco-Britannique, Paris, 1953 November 13 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - "Baroness Budberg," article, 1958 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - "The Prophets of Our Time" and "Lord Cameron", circa 1950 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    Chapters for a book entitled Giants Cast Long Shadows, which were not used. Draft typescripts
  - "Harold Macmillan," article, circa 1960 (Box-folder 6: 16)
- Sidney Reilly file, 1921-1968
  Article and correspondence relating to British espionage agent Sidney Reilly, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Article, "Kak îskal Shpiona Reīli," by R. I. Pimenov, 1968 June (Box-folder 6: 17)
    In Russian. Includes a partial English translation titled, "My Search for Reilly the Spy," Leningrad, 1968
  - Letters primarily to and from Sidney Reilly
    - General, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 6: 18)
      Letters to Mrs. Sidney Reilly from Harold Williams, 1925, and from C. D. R. Lumby and E. Marsh, 1927
    - Undated (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - Unidentified, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 6: 20)
      Includes telegrams to Sidney Reilly
    - Brunstrom, O., 1922 (Box-folder 6: 21)
    - Dukes, Paul, 1922 (Box-folder 6: 22)
    - Krary, Jim, 1921 (Box-folder 6: 23)
    - Savinkov, Boris, 1921-1924 (Box-folder 6: 24)
    - Spears, E. L., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 25)
      See also box 2 folder 10.
- Subject file, 1907-1960s
  Flyers, letters, maps, memoranda, pamphlet, reports, and miscellany relating primarily to the Soviet Union and Europe before and during World War II, arranged by subject
  - Alley, Stephen, undated (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Beaverbrook, Lord, 1954 May 23 (Box-folder 6: 27)
    Pamphlet of photographs commemorating Lord Beaverbrook's 75th birthday
  - Chester Concession
    - Affidavit, 1922 (Box-folder 6: 28)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box-folder 6: 29)
    - Letters, 1914-1923 (Box-folder 6: 30)
      Includes letters to K. B. Clayton-Kennedy
  - China, circa 1960 (Box-folder 6: 31)
    Notes on Chinese foreign relations, primarily with the Soviet Union. Holograph
  - Czechoslovakia, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 6: 32)
    Reports for the British Foreign Office on the meeting between Vyacheslav Molotov and Edvard Beneš in England, 1942 June; a memorandum regarding Czech frontiers, 1941; a memorandum by President Edvard Beneš on British radio broadcasts during World War II; and an incomplete letter, attributed to Mildred Thomas, describing Dr. Beneš' final illness, after the Communist take-over, 1948 October. Typescripts
  - De Valera, Eamon, 1945 October 19 (Box-folder 6: 33)
    Report of an interview with Eamon De Valera. Typescript
  - Masaryk, Ján, undated (Box-folder 6: 34)
    See also box 9 folder 15
    Photocopy of a medal issued by the Czechs to commemorate his death, and of a note by Lockhart.
  - Savinkov, Boris V.
    - Agenda, undated (Box-folder 6: 35)
      Contains agenda of a meeting where Savinkov was scheduled to give a speech on the Russian political situation.
    - Clipping, 1925 August (Box-folder 6: 36)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 6: 37-38)
      - Savinkova, S, 1922 (Box-folder 6: 39)
    - Report, undated (Box-folder 6: 40)
      Typescript fragments concerning the role of the Polish government in Savinkov's conspiracy against the Soviet government and a letter to the editor by Maslovski on the subject.
  - Soviet Union
    - General, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7: 1)
      Includes maps, World War I savings bonds, and a handwritten luggage receipt
    - British newspaper, The Socialist, with an article on the "Lockhart Plot", 1918 September (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Flyer issued by the Bolsheviks describing the "Lockhart Plot", 1918 September (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Pass signed by Leon Trotsky, 1918 February 27 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      Photocopy
    - Report to the British Foreign Office on a conversation with L. M. Karachan about relations between Soviet Union and the Allies (declassified), 1918 November 7 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Report (incomplete) by William B. Webster of the American Red Cross Mission to the Soviet Union on the post-war situation in the Baltic area, 1918 December 30 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - United States, 1939 April 15 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    Report to the British Foreign Office on the state of American public opinion on the situation in Europe. Typescript
  - William II, German Emperor, 1939 August (Box-folder 7: 8)
    Report on a visit. Typescript
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - Allied leaflet announcing the liberation of Paris, 1944 August (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Silk map prepared for intelligence agents during the North African invasion, 1942 September - October (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Summary of meetings between Winston Churchill, Anthony Eden, and Vyacheslav Molotov, 1942 June 10-11 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Miscellany, 1907-1938 (Box-folder 7: 12-14)
    Includes illustrations and postcards
- Great Britain Foreign Office documents, 1946-1948
  Mostly British Embassy, Prague, dispatches to the Foreign Office, but also from Denmark, France, Soviet Union, and United States, all relating to the situation in Czechoslovakia, arranged alphabetically by location of embassy
  - British Embassy
    - Czechoslovakia (Box-folder 8: 1-3)
    - Denmark (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - France (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Soviet Union (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - United States (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Photographs, 1912-1956
  32 prints and 1 negative depicting personalities such as Edvard Beneš, Arthur Henderson, David Lloyd George, and Ján Masaryk, arranged by physical form
  - Negatives, circa 1918 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    Contains 1 negative depicting inscription on silver box given by Sidney Reilly to Robert Lockhart.
  - Prints
    - 4 prints depicting unidentified individuals, undated (Box-folder 9: 2)
      See also box 1 folder 31
    - 1 print (photocopy) depicting inscription on silver box given by Sidney Reilly to Robert Lockhart, circa 1918 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 1 print of [Milner], undated (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 1 print depicting the city of Moscow, undated (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - 1 print depicting Feliks Dzerzhinskii, undated (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - 1 print depicting Arthur Henderson, undated (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - 1 print depicting Madame Germanova, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - 1 print depicting Artur Khristianovich Artuzov, Chief of the Counter Intelligence Department or KRO (Kontr-razvediavatel'nyi otdel'), undated (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - 1 print depicting Leon Trotsky, undated (Box-folder 9 :10)
    - 1 print depicting President Edvard Beneš and Ján Masaryk, undated (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - 1 print depicting Yakov Peters, undated (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - 1 print depicting leaders of the October Revolution, undated (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - 5 prints depicting David Lloyd George, Richard Tauber, and his wife, Diana Napier, in David Lloyd George's garden, undated (Box-folder 9: 14)
    - 2 prints including one depicting the graves of Ján Masaryk and T. C. Masaryk, and one depicting a medal issued by the Czechs to commemorate the death of Ján Masaryk, undated (Box-folder 9: 15)
      See also box 6 folder 34
    - 1 print of the late Reverend Lombard of Hampstead and St. Petersburg (Leningrad), 1912? (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - 3 prints depicting the Moscow Football Team, 1912-1916 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    - 1 print depicting an unidentified individual on top of the Empire State Building, circa 1936 (Box-folder 9: 18)
    - 4 prints depicting Edvard Beneš, President of Czechoslovakia, including one signed by him for Robert Lockhart,, one signed by President Edvard Beneš for Aston Abbotts,, one depicting him on his death bed, and one depicting his grave site, 1942, 1944, 1956 (Box-folder 9: 19)
    - 1 print depicting Moura Budberg (or possibly Kay Francis in the film role of Moura Budberg), undated (Box-folder 9: 20)
- Incremental materials
  Contains files of Robert H. Bruce Lockhart and Robin N. Bruce Lockhart, including materials related to Sidney Reilly.
  - Biographical file, 1906-1989
    Includes correspondence, clippings, notes, and miscellany.
    - Clippings, 1932-1988 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Personal file, 1937-1979 (Box-folder 10: 2)
      Includes correspondence, notes, and miscellany
    - Portrait file, 1989 (Box-folder 10: 3)
      Includes clippings and correspondence concerning a portrait of Robert Lockhart by K. Somov
    - Youth
      - Education, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 10: 4)
      - Malaya, 1906-circa 1938 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Diaries
    Contains correspondence and lists related to diaries.
    - Correspondence and lists, Records Office, House of Lords, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Speeches and writings, 1907-1986
    Includes notes on a discussion with Kaiser Wilhelm II, political writings, and poetry edited by Robin N. Bruce Lockhart, son of Robert H. Bruce Lockhart.
    - "Cities and Men," notes, undated (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - "Through the Jungle Softly," poetry, 1907-1986 (Box-folder 10: 8)
      Edited by Robin Bruce Lockhart.
    - "Notes on Kaiser Talks", 1939 (Box-folder 10: 9)
      Notes from meeting with Kaiser Wilhelm II
    - "Ten Years After: A Munich Survey", 1948 (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - "Last Words on Lenin", 1960 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Subject file, 1918-1961
    Includes correspondence and reports related to World War II and British government documents concerning Russia.
    - British government documents about Russia, 1918 (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - World War II
      - Beneš, Edvard, 1942 (Box-folder 10: 13)
      - Official appointments, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 10: 14)
      - Poland, undated (Box-folder 10: 15)
      - Post-war correspondence with Foreign Office, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - Photographs, circa 1910-1950s (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Robin N. Bruce Lockhart file, 1904-2003
    Contains the files of Robert Lockhart's son, Robin N. Bruce Lockhart, concerning Sidney Reilly.
    - Sidney Reilly and the Russian Revolution file, 1918-2002
      - Hill, George file
        - General, 1938, 1967, undated (Box-folder 10: 18-19)
        - Correspondence with Robin Lockhart, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 10: 20)
        - Correspondence with others, 1935-1945 (Box-folder 10: 21)
        - Estate, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 10: 22)
        - Legal documents, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 10: 23)